[theme music playing]
[Ivy] I want to be part
of Ardiente's progress.
I will support Congressman Julio Ardiente
in his bid for the Senate.
Just a piece of advice, Julio.
Be careful in dealing with her.
There's something about that woman.
Don't worry. I know what I'm doing.
I'm Julio Ardiente.
And I don't make mistakes.
[Arnaldo] Thank you for investing
in our project, by the way.
[Ivy] I don't need your thanks.
I invested a lot.
That means, Mr. Mayor,
I'll expect a lot in return.
My boyfriend is not a book.
Nor is he a toy
that can be borrowed or shared.
My boyfriend? He's mine.
[Ivy] You can have Arnaldo.
I don't like secondhand things.
I like my toys brand new.
How will you benefit
from investing in Ardiente?
Never mind. I already know the answer.
[Emilia] Use your head.
You're so stupid!
-[Diego] Mom.
-That's enough, Governor.
I'd never entrust my life
to anyone I think is stupid.
I'm sorry, but you may leave.
[Carlotta] Calm down.
All that anger won't do you any good.
Jepoy, what did they do to my mother?
[Ivy wailing]
[knocking on door]
Come in.
Grandpa.
You're giving me tea?
Do I look weak to you?
Grandpa, you're not getting any younger.
Tea is better for you than alcohol.
Don't waste my time, boy.
What do you need?
I'm just worried about the farmers.
Grandpa, they worked on that land
their entire lives.
We can't just force them to leave.
I can do whatever I want
and they can't do anything about it.
My project there will push through.
But Grandpa,
you promised you'd give them that land
during the last elections.
Aren't you going to keep your word?
Are you telling me what to do?
[tense music playing]
It's not like that.
I'm just reminding you in case you forgot.
Drinking alcohol every night
could affect a person's memory.
Shut up, Diego.
How many times do I have to
remind you that your farmers
are just like worker ants?
Their role in life
is to simply serve those above them.
That's us.
You may have lost weight
and gained muscle,
but your brain has dried up.
No, it hasn't.
I just see things clearer now.
You studied
community development.
Is that
what you're so proud of?
They shouldn't have let you
study in that university
filled with activists.
You may leave, Diego.
I'll leave,
but this won't be the last time I fight
for the people of this town.
You should rest, Grandpa.
Thanks for the tea, by the way.
Dad?
-Yeah?
-Where are you going?
I just have to do something real quick.
Go to bed.
Maybe in a while.
What is it?
[sighs]
I spoke to Grandpa.
[scoffs]
You know what, son? I'll be frank.
If this is about those farmers
you want to help,
just drop it because you will never change
your grandfather's decision.
But Dad, I just want to fight
for their rights.
But you won't win.
Because no matter what you do
for the people here,
you can't change their lives.
As long as this family
is in power, nothing will change.
Just accept that, son.
[light piano music playing]
If you can stay away from trouble, do it.
I don't want anything bad
happening to you.
I have to go.
Take care, Dad.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[shoveling sound]
[sobbing]
You know, Mom?
Every day, I ask myself…
why this happened to us.
Why did this happen to our family?
Why us, Mom? Why us?
Why did this happen to us?
[instrumental theme music playing]
I feel nothing but…
pain…
anger…
and fury.
That's what I feel when I think
about the people
who did this to you.
[ominous music playing]
I'm furious, Mom.
I promise you and Dad…
I'll avenge your deaths.
I will avenge you both.
[tense music playing]
Ivy?
Ivy, wait! Ivy!
Ivy!
[tense music playing]
[Raul] No matter what you do
for the people here,
you can't change their lives.
As long as this family is in power,
nothing will change.
Just accept that, son.
I still believe there's hope
for this town.
If I was able to change for the better…
then I can change this whole place too.
[dramatic music playing]
Someday, I'll change all of Ardiente.
And my family too.
[brooding music playing]
LONG LIVE!
CONGRESSMAN JULIO ARDIENTE
[Emilia] Maids like you
should have presence of mind.
Use your head.
You're so stupid!
Can you further extend
your assistance to Poblacion Ardiente?
[Pablo] Be careful around Julio.
He's clever, like you.
[brooding music playing]
[Emilia] Didn't you start all this?
If only you didn't take a liking
to that girl's mother,
her father wouldn't have gone against us!
[Raul] You enjoyed murdering those people.
You wiped out an entire family!
[Ivy] How could they do this to her?
[Ivy wailing]
Mom!
[tense music playing]
[Julio] As long as this statue
stands firm in our town,
you will continue to have
honest service and leadership
as promised by
your very own Governor Julio!
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[banging]
Crook!
You bastard! You monster!
You monster! You killed my parents!
You killed my parents! You're monsters!
[shouting] You monsters!
[sobbing] You're all monsters!
You monsters.
I'll kill you all.
I'll kill all of you Ardientes!
[shouting] Ardientes!
[shouting] You monsters!
Ivy! Ivy!
[Ivy wailing]
-I'll kill them all!
-What did you do?
They're monsters.
We have to go now. Ivy.
Come on.
[Ivy crying]
Hold on.
They're monsters.
[gentle music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
NEW ARDIENTE
[Diego] Good morning!
-[Pandoy] Diego!
-[Loring] What--
Do you like it?
It's nice.
[Pandoy] Oh? Oh!
"New Ardiente"?
Can we still have that?
Is change still possible in this place?
Of course, Uncle!
Like they say, everything changes.
The only constant thing
is the speed of light.
What?
What Diego meant was,
"When there's life, there's hope."
You're right, Auntie.
-I told you so!
-Okay.
How was the party last night?
It was awful.
Grandpa announced that
their project here will push through.
What? That fast?
They got more than enough funds
from the huge amount
Ivy Aguas invested.
Some rich people are unbelievable.
All they think about is earning money.
She should just leave our town.
As long as she's here,
it'll be difficult
to change my family's mind.
Their greed for money is getting worse!
What are we going to do, then?
Your grandfather's project
has to be stopped.
[tense music]
NEW ARDIENTE
[instrumental theme music playing]
Ivy, you're awake.
Here. I brought you breakfast.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Ivy, I'm worried about you.
You might get in trouble for what you did.
Nanny.
I won't.
I'm sure Jepoy will do his job.
[sighs deeply]
It felt so good, Nanny.
When I managed to…
wreck…
smash…
and destroy
the Ardientes' symbol of power.
It felt amazing.
Ivy. Take it easy.
Don't let your anger consume you.
Hmm?
I won't let that happen.
Here,
now, I am Ivy Aguas.
I'll use this identity
to grip the Ardientes
in the palm of my hand.
This is Ivy, not Lily. This isn't Lily.
Now…
I'll work on completely
winning Emilia's trust.
That's my current goal.
-Nanny, don't worry.
-Okay.
[woman] Rice cakes! Rice cakes!
[tense music playing]
Oh no!
I'm sorry, but I can't eat right now.
The Ardientes invited me over
for breakfast.
I'm excited to see them.
I'm excited to see the look on their faces
once they find out
Julio's statue was destroyed.
I can't wait to see
the look on their faces.
-I'll go get ready.
-Go ahead, dear.
[utensils clanking]
How's your arm, Governor?
It's better now.
I applied imported
burn ointment cream on it.
I'm fine now.
-That's good to hear.
-Mm-hm.
Uh, aren't we short two people?
Oh, Raul is in a nearby town,
managing our business there.
Diego, on the other hand,
is with the farmers.
-Diego's with the farmers?
-[Emilia] Yes.
He must be close to them.
So, why didn't he enter politics,
like Arnaldo?
[gentle music playing]
[chuckles]
Let's just say
Diego is not equipped
or suited for politics.
Really, Congressman?
If he's close to the farmers,
that means Diego can sympathize
with the less fortunate.
Well,
let's look at it this way.
Diego doesn't have the stomach
to make hard and difficult decisions.
You know, Ivy, in politics,
sympathizing with people isn't enough.
You have to be tough
most of the time.
Well, anyway.
Let's not talk about people
who aren't here.
Let's talk about the future.
The bright future.
Your future here, in Ardiente.
Like your investment.
We can talk about that.
[man] Excuse me, Gov.
Chief is outside.
He wants to see Congressman.
Can you please tell him
to wait? Papa's still eating.
Gov, it's very important.
Fine, let him in.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] Well.
Good morning, Gov,
Mayor, Congressman.
[Julio] Good morning.
It's okay, she's our guest.
Just tell us whatever you have to say.
Uh, Congressman. Your statue at the plaza…
[tense drum beat]
…it was destroyed.
-Papa? Who did this?
-How did that happen?
Oh no, Papa.
This is really bad.
This is not good, Papa!
[Julio groans] Um…
Arnaldo. Arnaldo, take me to the plaza.
I want to see what happened to my statue.
Yes, Grandpa.
Miss Aguas, I'm sorry.
I will have to leave you
in the hands of Emilia.
I understand, Congressman.
-Thank you.
-[Ivy] I hope everything's okay.
Governor.
This is not happening.
Nanny,
get my cigarettes! Hurry!
Gov, relax.
This is not happening.
[Emilia sighs]
[cans clanking]
[Arthur panting]
[shouting] It's here!
The day has finally arrived!
The entire town will be destroyed!
Everyone who worships
that statue will be punished!
[Arthur laughing]
We're in trouble with Mayor
and Congressman.
They're going to call us
incompetent again.
"As long as this statue
stands in our town,
you'll have honest service."
[laughs]
But it broke!
If we could just pin it all
on that nutjob, it'd be over.
[Arthur] It broke!
[tense music playing]
[heavy breathing]
Someone wants to bring us down.
Someone with the nerve
to do it this publicly.
I'll make sure to capture
and punish whoever did this.
They're utterly disrespectful.
Our people must not assume
that we're getting weak.
Any updates? Have you found a lead?
I'm sorry, Mayor.
We didn't find any evidence.
All we have is this surveillance footage.
Arnaldo.
Take it.
Seal off the whole plaza.
When I return,
I want my statue rebuilt again.
Yes, Grandpa.
[ominous music playing]
Gov, don't worry.
I'm sure Congressman will fix everything.
After all,
this is Poblacion Ardiente.
Zero crime rate ever since--
Forever.
But honestly, I'm scared
for the person who did this.
For sure, they'll be punished in no time.
You know that I don't want
my people getting hurt.
I can't help but wonder.
Who would do such a thing?
[tense music playing]
Who else…
but our rivals in politics.
That's exactly why it's hard
to trust anyone these days.
Anyway, I have to go now.
If you need anything,
just call me.
Thank you, Ivy.
You're really a true friend,
not just to me but the whole Ardiente.
Thank you.
It feels so good
to be considered a friend by the governor.
-Thank you, Gov.
-Bye.
Bye.
Take care, okay?
[car engine starts]
-Bye!
-Take care.
[tense music playing]
We can now identify the bastard
who wants to ruin us.
[tense music playing]
-Huh?
-What happened?
Why did the footage disappear?
Perhaps someone switched it off
on purpose.
[brooding music playing]
I took care of everything.
I understand why you did it.
If it were me, I would've done
something much worse.
Jepoy, thank you.
You're always there to help me.
And to catch me when I fall.
[sighs deeply]
For you…
I'll do anything.
[brooding music playing]
[water splashes]
I hate feeling like we're
being played by our enemies.
We have to get to the bottom
of this as soon as possible.
Do you understand?
[sighs]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Dante] "Time flies so fast, doesn't it?
It feels like just yesterday
when I cried as I first held you.
Do you remember the day
I taught you how to ride a bike?
You fell a lot, but you kept getting up.
You're a very strong and determined girl.
In the near future,
thank yourself for those traits."
[instrumental theme music playing]
First, my failed
assassination, and now this.
Papa! These attacks worry me.
What are our enemies up to?
[tense music]
Where is Raul?
[Raul] Auntie.
No need for you to stand up. Sit down.
-[Belen] You're back so soon.
-Yeah.
Why? Did something happen? Anything new?
Just the usual. I didn't think
you'd be back right away.
I don't plan on staying long.
All they know is I had
some errands to run.
It's good you haven't run out
of excuses to come here.
I haven't.
-Coffee?
-No, thanks.
I'll just check on our friend.
-Okay, go right in.
-Thanks.
Whenever something happens, he's not here.
Papa,
don't tell me you think Raul--
Don't be stupid, Emilia.
Your husband
is a coward and a weakling.
If his disgraced father hadn't saved me,
I would have silenced that idiot long ago.
-Papa!
-No matter. Forget it. Forget it.
It's better for him to busy himself
with the operations
of our main source of income.
Money has to keep coming in.
[tense music]
Thirty-eight million.
[Joan]
Sold to our dear Mr. Senator.
[Pablo]
Julio and I are good friends.
He helped me win in the last elections.
It's my turn to help him.
[action music playing]
SENATOR PABLO ALCANTARA
PASSES ANTI-JUETENG BILL
[Emilia] Don't worry, Papa.
I'll add more men around
the premises to protect us.
You mean additional security?
Are you
out of your mind, Emilia?
Do you want us to look like
cowards and idiots
in the eyes of our enemies?
-That's not what I meant--
-Shut up!
Let the men handle this.
A woman like you wouldn't
understand anything.
Sorry, Papa.
I was just suggesting.
We are not going to give
our enemies the satisfaction
of seeing us running scared.
We will handle this but discreetly.
Arnaldo.
Monitor
who goes in and out of town.
Get a list of all the names
of those visiting Poblacion Ardiente.
From the very day of the attempted
assassination on your mother.
And do
a background check on all of them.
Oh. Papa,
does this include Ivy?
Especially Ivy.
I know we did
a background check on her already, but…
these things started
the moment she came here.
But Papa, she saved my life.
She even
invested in our project,
so why would we assume she's against us?
Have you really learned
nothing at all, Emilia?
In the world of politics,
any of your allies
can sometimes be your greatest enemy.
Must I keep drilling that into your head?
I'll handle Ivy, Papa.
I'll uncover
her deepest secrets.
Don't fail me, Emilia.
[ominous music playing]
-[Loring] Here. Here.
-[Pandoy] Everyone, let's eat! Come on.
-Did that tire you, son?
-It's good.
-[man] Here we go.
-Wow, banana fritters!
[townsfolk cheering]
[Fernan] Come dig in!
Don't be shy. Go get some.
-Fritters!
-[Fernan] Use your hands.
[Fernan] Our harvest
has been fruitful! We got lucky!
Mister Fernan, let's not forget
to thank Diego
for teaching us
the new technologies in farming.
We reaped so much!
-That's right.
-[all chanting] Diego!
[chanting] Diego!
Thank you. Thank you, everyone.
I'm happy with our harvest this year too.
But…
we have a huge problem.
I was at the party last night.
And I found out that…
the project will push through here.
It's good to hear the mayor
and congressman's project
will push through.
I'm sure it'll be beneficial to all of us.
Are you serious? That's not true!
If the project happens,
most of our land and even
this cooperative will disappear!
Come on!
We'll have to move? That's not right!
We've been cultivating this land
for so long.
Do they think we'll leave so easily?
-[townsfolk] He's right.
-[man] Mr. Diego, what's this about?
Diego, is it true they'll force us out?
[man] Sir?
We'll find a way so none of you
will get affected.
I will make sure your complaints
will reach the congressman.
We'll send a formal complaint
to his office.
-Thank you, Mr. Diego.
-Thank you.
[man] We're counting on you, sir.
[Joan] Miss Aguas, I'll just inform you
once we finalize the date
and the time of the conference call.
Okay, Joan. Thank you.
[Emilia] Yes, I'm on my way.
I'll just drop by Miss Aguas' place.
Okay, bye.
[pensive music playing]
[phone ringing]
Yes, Jepoy?
Hello, Ivy? Emilia's on her way there.
[tense music playing]
Really?
No worries. I've prepared for her arrival.
-Sweetie?
-Nanny.
-I'll go buy groceries, okay?
-All right. Stay safe, okay?
Oh, I do have a favor to ask.
Remember that blabbermouth at the market?
Can you talk to her?
Just ask her about what happened
to Julio's statue.
All right, dear. You can count on me.
-Thank you. Take care.
-You too.
[tense music playing]
[dramatic music]
Ma'am.
Ivy.
Governor?
Governor, what a surprise!
We were
just together a while ago.
[Emilia] Hi!
Juice or, I know it's still
early, but champagne maybe?
No, I'm fine.
I'll pass this time.
I still
need to go to the town hall.
I came here to deliver this.
[light music playing]
Governor, I'm a little worried.
This morning, my helpers
went to the market
and told me what happened
to Congressman's statue
is the talk of the town.
[chuckles]
I guess it's true what they say,
that news travels fast.
And the market
is the breeding ground of flies,
rats, and rumors!
[scoffs]
Don't worry, Ivy.
We are doing something about it.
As we speak, the people
behind it are being apprehended.
But everything that's
been happening got me thinking.
It's bothering me.
What do you mean?
Governor, now that someone's openly
going against you, it's troubling.
I'm starting
to reconsider my investment.
-[Diego] Can you load these on the truck?
-[man] Yes, sir!
[indistinct chatter]
Wait!
Why does everyone look so dull?
Come on, guys.
Can we forget about our problem
with the land for a while?
Let's enjoy our amazing harvest!
Why don't we have a feast tomorrow?
Yes! Let's do that! That's a great idea!
I'll cook some banana fritters
for dessert tomorrow.
But you have to pay
for what you ate today.
-Miss Loring, come on!
-[Loring] Just kidding!
-I thought…
-That's great!
We're like a family here.
We might have our differences,
but we all agree when it comes
to our land and harvest.
-That's true.
-That's right, boss.
This is where I get money
to send my son to school.
And this is the only way
I can afford my mother's medicine.
This is for my son's school allowance.
See that? All of us depend on this land.
So, if it'll be taken from us
just because
of that new project, what then?
-That's right.
-Right.
-Exactly.
-Wait.
Write in here all you
want to say to the congressman.
I promise you
I'll deliver it to him myself.
-Boss, can I go first?
-Sure.
-Everyone!
-What happened, Cora?
-Ms. Loring.
-What took you so long?
And why are you out of breath?
There's news going around town.
What news?
The congressman's statue
was destroyed last night!
-What?
-That's right.
[woman] Who could've done it?
Come on, Ivy.
I thought we're friends!
Of course, we are!
But this is different.
This is business!
Yes, I understand.
But you know
I won't let you do that, right?
You know why?
Because we're friends!
I want you to earn well,
which won't happen
if you pull out of your investment.
Governor, I don't need to earn money.
I'm already rich, remember?
I can buy anything I want.
What matters to me is I protect
my reputation and my company.
I don't want to get involved
with any issues.
And since you're in politics,
I'm sure you understand me.
Of course, Ivy.
I completely understand.
But you know, once you're in bed
with an Ardiente,
you can't just easily back out.
And after all, we publicly
announced our partnership.
You wouldn't want to
humiliate a friend, right?
And a true friend
never backs out on a promise.
But I haven't promised anything yet.
I mean, I haven't signed
any contracts yet.
Is that it? Don't worry.
I'll have the papers ready
by tomorrow, so you can sign them.
But it's not that easy, Governor.
Of course, my lawyers
still need to check it.
And if they're okay with it,
then we won't have a problem.
Of course!
Anyway, I have to go.
I need
to head to the town hall.
You know,
my constituents are waiting.
Thank you.
-Governor.
-Yes?
As your friend,
I want you to be extra careful.
I'm sure your enemies
are watching your every move.
Oh no, sweetheart.
I don't need to be careful.
They're the ones who have to be.
Bye!
[somber music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[gun cocks]
[gunshots ring out]
Whoever you are going against
my family, I'll make you suffer.
You'll pay for this.
[gunshot rings out]
[panting]
I'll deploy my elite team
to watch over our checkpoints.
I don't want
just your elite team, Superintendent.
I would suggest getting officers
from the provincial headquarters too.
After the tampering
with the security footage from the plaza,
I've lost my trust
in the police force in our town.
Noted, Congressman.
Thank you, Superintendent.
You may go.
Good morning, ma'am.
Papa, look at this.
Oh. Why do you have this?
Papa.
I have to lock down
the deal with Ivy as soon as possible.
Before she changes her mind.
She knows what's happening.
Wait. What did you do
to make her back out?
I didn't do anything, Papa.
Don't be a liar, Emilia.
You must've done something
for her to change her mind.
You're such a worthless person!
-That's so unfair, Papa.
-Shut up.
We have to fix this.
We need that woman and her money.
Yes, Papa.
Emilia.
Please,
don't do anything anymore.
Talk to Arnaldo.
He can handle this
better than you.
Arnaldo knows
how to charm that woman.
Go.
[tense music playing]
You'll go down, Ardientes.
[Arthur giggling]
-They're here. [laughs]
-Shh.
Our savior has come to this town.
They'll bring you down!
[raspberry sound]
-What did you say?
-Mayor. Mayor. Mayor!
Hold on. I got this.
[wicked laugh]
I saw. I saw them.
[suspenseful music playing]
A woman
and a man.
They had a sledgehammer.
They destroyed the statue.
[Arthur chuckling]
-I saw them!
-Uh…
I saw them!
-Wait! Where…
-Ardiente is going down!
-Hey! Stop!
[Arthur laughing]
Grandpa. I heard what happened.
[tense music playing]
It doesn't concern you, Diego.
Stay out of this.
But I'm worried about you.
There's no need.
This is the first and last time
that I let anyone openly oppose me.
[tense music playing]
[Diego] Don't try to fool the farmers.
You're just after the land, right?
You're smart enough to see that.
And you're beautiful too.
It's a shame you don't have a good heart.
You're giving me a hard time,
and I'm not liking it.
If the congressman were the one asking me,
I might say yes to him.
You don't know what you're talking about.
I can read you like a book,
Governor Emilia.
From head to toe.
Someone saw you destroying the statue.
-[Ivy] What?
-[Jepoy] His name is Arthur. He's nuts.
Who ordered you?
I'll talk! I'll talk!
[theme music playing]